<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="part2stratml.xsl"?>
<PerformancePlanOrReport xmlns="urn:ISO:std:iso:17469:tech:xsd:PerformancePlanOrReport" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"

 xsi:schemaLocation="urn:ISO:std:iso:17469:tech:xsd:PerformancePlanOrReport http://stratml.us/references/PerformancePlanOrReport20160216.xsd" Type="Strategic_Plan"><Name>About OntoInsights</Name><Description>Deep Narrative Analysis ~ Greater Insights by Enabling All Voices to be Heard</Description><OtherInformation/><StrategicPlanCore><Organization><Name>OntoInsights, LLC</Name><Acronym>ONTIN</Acronym><Identifier>_0eaf2c34-c5ef-11ee-8d75-0973ff82ea00</Identifier><Description>OntoInsights LLC provides software services, support and consultation to customers who are interested in using narrative analysis to further their business goals.</Description><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Person"><Name>Andrea Westerinen</Name><Description>Founder and CTO ~ Ms. Westerinen has over 30 years of technical management and leadership experience in government and commercial spaces. She holds an MS in Computer Science from Nova Southeastern University and a BS in Physics/Mathematics from Marquette University. Ms. Westerinen has filed 8 patents as inventor or co-inventor (6 issued to-date).</Description></Stakeholder><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Person"><Name>Jeff Westerinen</Name><Description>CEO ~ Mr. Westerinen has over 33 years of executive management and product leadership experience at Microsoft, Intel, NCR and IBM. He holds an MS in Mechanical Engineering and a BS in Biochemistry, from the State University of New York at Stony Brook. Mr. Westerinen has filed over 100 patents as inventor or co-inventor (over 70 issued to-date).</Description></Stakeholder><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Person"><Name>Jeffrey Ried</Name><Description>Partnerships ~ Jeffrey Ried, PhD, brings over 15 years of experience in building partnerships and catalyzing change in multicultural settings. He has held leadership positions in non-profit, philanthropic, and government organizations in the US and Africa including the Gates Foundation and Ethiopia’s Agricultural Transformation Agency. He and his wife co-founded and operate the nonprofit Ethiopian Education Fund.</Description></Stakeholder><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Person"><Name>Becky Jackson</Name><Description>Ms. Jackson has seven years of experience working with various academic groups on the development of biological and biomedical ontologies with a focus in automating development and quality control. She holds a BS in Computer Science/Biology from University of Maryland. Ms. Jackson is an author on over ten scientific papers on the subject of ontologies &amp; ontology development with more in progress.</Description></Stakeholder><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Person"><Name>Marty Jackson</Name><Description>Mr. Jackson has over five years of experience as a Data Scientist in various industries. He designs and builds predictive state models for automating machine learning pipelines. Mr. Jackson holds an MA in Economics from American University and a BA in Economics from Bucknell University.</Description></Stakeholder></Organization><Vision><Description>All voices are heard</Description><Identifier>_0eaf2cfc-c5ef-11ee-8d75-0973ff82ea00</Identifier></Vision><Mission><Description>To use narrative analysis to further business goals</Description><Identifier>_0eaf2d92-c5ef-11ee-8d75-0973ff82ea00</Identifier></Mission><Value><Name>Communication</Name><Description>Storytelling has been the primary mode of human communication for more than 300,000 years.</Description></Value><Value><Name>Storytelling</Name><Description>Humans are pre-wired to be influenced by a good story. In today’s hyperconnected world, a good story can dramatically increase the virility of a news flash.</Description></Value><Value><Name>Influence</Name><Description>A good story can catch fire through social media and on-line news sources and have the power to sway elections.</Description></Value><Value><Name>Empowerment</Name><Description>And a good story can give a voice to the unempowered.</Description></Value><Value><Name>Knowledge</Name><Description>OntoInsights LLC is founded on the belief that we can significantly improve knowledge acquisition and understanding of human narrative by combining artificial intelligence with semantic technologies.</Description></Value><Value><Name>Understanding</Name><Description/></Value><Goal><Name>Narratives</Name><Description>Conduct analysis of narratives</Description><Identifier>_0eaf2e82-c5ef-11ee-8d75-0973ff82ea00</Identifier><SequenceIndicator/><Stakeholder><Name/><Description/></Stakeholder><OtherInformation/><Objective><Name>Consultations</Name><Description>Offer consulting services in the emerging areas of using ontologies and semantic analysis</Description><Identifier>_0eaf2f04-c5ef-11ee-8d75-0973ff82ea00</Identifier><SequenceIndicator>1</SequenceIndicator><Stakeholder><Name/><Description/></Stakeholder><OtherInformation>We offer consulting services in the emerging areas of using ontologies and semantic analysis for exploring, investigating and linking narrative texts.</OtherInformation></Objective><Objective><Name>Tools</Name><Description>Create a tool set enabling comparison and analysis of knowledge</Description><Identifier>_0eaf2f86-c5ef-11ee-8d75-0973ff82ea00</Identifier><SequenceIndicator>2</SequenceIndicator><Stakeholder><Name/><Description/></Stakeholder><OtherInformation>In addition, we are working to create an open source tool set enabling non-technical users to compare and deeply analyze individual, group and organizational knowledge, as communicated in narratives and stories.</OtherInformation></Objective></Goal></StrategicPlanCore><AdministrativeInformation><StartDate/><EndDate/><PublicationDate>2024-02-07</PublicationDate><Source>https://www.ontoinsights.com/</Source><Submitter><GivenName>Owen</GivenName><Surname>Ambur</Surname><PhoneNumber/><EmailAddress>Owen.Ambur@verizon.net</EmailAddress></Submitter></AdministrativeInformation></PerformancePlanOrReport>