<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PerformancePlanOrReport xmlns="urn:ISO:std:iso:17469:tech:xsd:PerformancePlanOrReport" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="urn:ISO:std:iso:17469:tech:xsd:PerformancePlanOrReport http://stratml.us/references/PerformancePlanOrReport20160216.xsd" Type="Strategic_Plan"><Name>About OECD.AI</Name><Description>OECD.AI combines resources from across the OECD, its partners and all stakeholder groups. OECD.AI facilitates dialogue between stakeholders while providing multidisciplinary, evidence-based policy analysis in the areas where AI has the most impact. As an inclusive platform for public policy on AI – the OECD AI Policy Observatory is oriented around three core attributes [documented as goals in this StratML rendition]</Description><OtherInformation>The OECD AI Policy Observatory (OECD.AI) builds on the momentum of the OECD’s Recommendation on Artificial Intelligence (“OECD AI Principles”) – the first intergovernmental standard on AI – adopted in May 2019 by OECD countries and adhered to by range of partner economies. The OECD AI Principles provided the basis for the G20 AI Principles endorsed by Leaders in June 2019.</OtherInformation><StrategicPlanCore><Organization><Name>OECD.AI Policy Observatory</Name><Acronym>AIPO</Acronym><Identifier>_b9806f30-b1a1-11ea-a710-051b2b83ea00</Identifier><Description>The OECD.AI Policy Observatory combines resources from across the OECD and its partners from all stakeholder groups. It facilitates dialogue and provides multidisciplinary, evidence-based policy analysis and data on AI’s areas of impact.</Description><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Organization"><Name>Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development</Name><Description>Convening power &amp; community: the OECD’s added value Like computing, electrification, and the steam engine, AI is a general-purpose technology with transformative potential in a wide variety of sectors and with implications for the whole of society. In this increasingly active research and policy space, the OECD AI Policy Observatory provides a valuable reference for international dialogue and collaboration on AI public policy issues. As an international organisation spanning almost every public policy topic, the OECD can provide multidisciplinary, evidence-based policy analysis on AI across the full range of economic and social policy issues, as well as metrics and measurement. The OECD’s convening power and robust multi-stakeholder approach allows the facilitation of co-operation among the private sector, the technical community, civil society, academia, governments, the regulatory community and other international organisations. Moreover, the OECD’s global reach allows countries and stakeholders to compare policy responses, learn from each other’s experiences, monitor collective progress and develop good practices.</Description><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Generic_Group"><Name>OECD.AI Team</Name><Description>The OECD.AI team is multinational, multicultural and multi-disciplinary. Its members have backgrounds in engineering, computing, economics, law and political science from institutions in Europe, the Americas, the Middle East and Asia.</Description><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Generic_Group"><Name>ONE AI</Name><Description>OECD Network of Experts on AI (ONE AI) -- The OECD Network of Experts on AI (ONE AI) provides policy, technical and business expert input to inform OECD analysis and recommendations. It is a multi-disciplinary and multi-stakeholder group.</Description><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Generic_Group"><Name>OECD.AI Partners</Name><Description>To inform policy, the OECD welcomes cooperative relationships with other actors with complementary technical, business or policy expertise. It welcomes data and insights on AI developments with an eye on international reach. Partnerships &amp; implementation -- The development of AI is driven by activities and investments across a wide range of stakeholders, and a wealth of information, data and knowledge is therefore outside government. To understand developments in AI and to gather related data and knowledge, OECD.AI seeks cooperations with governmental, non-governmental and inter-governmental actors with complementary and demonstrated data; technical, business or policy expertise; insight on AI developments; and a wide international reach.</Description><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Organization"><Name>Jožef Stefan Institute</Name><Description>Currently, OECD.AI is working closely with the Jožef Stefan Institute (JSI) in Slovenia, whose AI Lab is working with the OECD to provide live metrics on OECD.AI.</Description><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Organization"><Name>Microsoft Research</Name><Description>OECD.AI is also collaborating with, and leveraging data and information from Event Registry, Microsoft Research – which has developed Microsoft Academic Graph – as well as LinkedIn.</Description><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Organization"><Name>EC Joint Research Centre</Name><Description>OECD.AI is working with the European Commission’s Joint Research Centre, in the context of OECD.AI’s section on national AI policies and strategies.</Description><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Organization"><Name>Université Laval</Name><Description>OECD.AI also plan to cooperate with the International observatory on the societal impacts of artificial intelligence and digital technology (OBVIA) hosted by Université Laval in Canada, which has similar research interests and offers the potential to exchange with the dynamic AI ecosystem in Quebec.</Description><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder></Organization><Vision><Description>Adherence to OECD AI Principles</Description><Identifier>_b98070d4-b1a1-11ea-a710-051b2b83ea00</Identifier></Vision><Mission><Description>To facilitate dialogue and provide policy analysis on AI</Description><Identifier>_b98071b0-b1a1-11ea-a710-051b2b83ea00</Identifier></Mission><Value><Name/><Description/></Value><Goal><Name>Multidisciplinarity</Name><Description>Consider opportunities and challenges posed by current and future AI developments in a coherent, holistic manner</Description><Identifier>_b98072c8-b1a1-11ea-a710-051b2b83ea00</Identifier><SequenceIndicator>1</SequenceIndicator><Stakeholder><Name/><Description/><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder><OtherInformation>The Observatory works with policy communities across and beyond the OECD – from the digital economy and science and technology policy, to employment, health, consumer protection, education and transport policy – to consider the opportunities and challenges posed by current and future AI developments in a coherent, holistic manner.</OtherInformation><Objective><Name/><Description/><Identifier>_b9807386-b1a1-11ea-a710-051b2b83ea00</Identifier><SequenceIndicator/><Stakeholder><Name/><Description/><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder><OtherInformation/><PerformanceIndicator ><SequenceIndicator/><MeasurementDimension/><UnitOfMeasurement/><Identifier>_166e8856-40aa-11ec-97d4-7f2e60babdf6</Identifier><Relationship><Identifier>PLACEHOLDER_1</Identifier><ReferentIdentifier/><Name/><Description/></Relationship><MeasurementInstance><TargetResult><Description/><Descriptor><DescriptorName/><DescriptorValue/></Descriptor><StartDate/><EndDate/></TargetResult><ActualResult><Description>[To be determined]</Description><Descriptor><DescriptorName/><DescriptorValue/></Descriptor><StartDate/><EndDate/></ActualResult></MeasurementInstance><OtherInformation/></PerformanceIndicator></Objective></Goal><Goal><Name>Analysis</Name><Description>Provide a centre for the collection and sharing of evidence on AI</Description><Identifier>_b980744e-b1a1-11ea-a710-051b2b83ea00</Identifier><SequenceIndicator>2</SequenceIndicator><Stakeholder><Name/><Description/><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder><OtherInformation>Evidence-based analysis -- The Observatory provides a centre for the collection and sharing of evidence on AI, leveraging the OECD’s reputation for measurement methodologies and evidence-based analysis.</OtherInformation><Objective><Name/><Description/><Identifier>_b9807516-b1a1-11ea-a710-051b2b83ea00</Identifier><SequenceIndicator/><Stakeholder><Name/><Description/><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder><OtherInformation/><PerformanceIndicator ><SequenceIndicator/><MeasurementDimension/><UnitOfMeasurement/><Identifier>_166e8b08-40aa-11ec-97d4-7f2e60babdf6</Identifier><Relationship><Identifier>PLACEHOLDER_2</Identifier><ReferentIdentifier/><Name/><Description/></Relationship><MeasurementInstance><TargetResult><Description/><Descriptor><DescriptorName/><DescriptorValue/></Descriptor><StartDate/><EndDate/></TargetResult><ActualResult><Description>[To be determined]</Description><Descriptor><DescriptorName/><DescriptorValue/></Descriptor><StartDate/><EndDate/></ActualResult></MeasurementInstance><OtherInformation/></PerformanceIndicator></Objective></Goal><Goal><Name>Partnerships</Name><Description>Engage stakeholders and provide a hub for dialogue and collaboration</Description><Identifier>_b98075de-b1a1-11ea-a710-051b2b83ea00</Identifier><SequenceIndicator>3</SequenceIndicator><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Generic_Group"><Name>Governments</Name><Description/><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Generic_Group"><Name>Technical Community</Name><Description/><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Generic_Group"><Name>Private Sector</Name><Description/><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Generic_Group"><Name>Academia</Name><Description/><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Generic_Group"><Name>Civil Society</Name><Description/><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder><Stakeholder StakeholderTypeType="Generic_Group"><Name>International Organisations</Name><Description/><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder><OtherInformation>Global multi-stakeholder partnerships -- The Observatory engages governments and a wide spectrum of stakeholders – including partners from the technical community, the private sector, academia, civil society and other international organisations – and provides a hub for dialogue and collaboration.</OtherInformation><Objective><Name/><Description/><Identifier>_b98076a6-b1a1-11ea-a710-051b2b83ea00</Identifier><SequenceIndicator/><Stakeholder><Name/><Description/><Role><Name/><Description/></Role></Stakeholder><OtherInformation/><PerformanceIndicator ><SequenceIndicator/><MeasurementDimension/><UnitOfMeasurement/><Identifier>_166e8c20-40aa-11ec-97d4-7f2e60babdf6</Identifier><Relationship><Identifier>PLACEHOLDER_3</Identifier><ReferentIdentifier/><Name/><Description/></Relationship><MeasurementInstance><TargetResult><Description/><Descriptor><DescriptorName/><DescriptorValue/></Descriptor><StartDate/><EndDate/></TargetResult><ActualResult><Description>[To be determined]</Description><Descriptor><DescriptorName/><DescriptorValue/></Descriptor><StartDate/><EndDate/></ActualResult></MeasurementInstance><OtherInformation/></PerformanceIndicator></Objective></Goal></StrategicPlanCore><AdministrativeInformation><Identifier>_166e8d10-40aa-11ec-97d4-7f2e60babdf6</Identifier><StartDate/><EndDate/><PublicationDate>2020-06-18</PublicationDate><Source>https://oecd.ai/about</Source></AdministrativeInformation><Submitter><Identifier>_166e8f90-40aa-11ec-97d4-7f2e60babdf6</Identifier><GivenName>Owen</GivenName><Surname>Ambur</Surname><PhoneNumber/><EmailAddress>Owen.Ambur@verizon.net</EmailAddress></Submitter></PerformancePlanOrReport>